Evan Velasco

1350 E St SE Apt #394, Washington, DC 20003 - (805) 657-5838 - evan.velasco@live.com

Summary

Analytics professional with 4 years of experience in advertising technology and monetization, specializing in extracting business insights from massive datasets. Experience with ad-hoc analysis, ETL, data warehousing, dashboarding, A/B testing, forecasting, and data driven product development. Possesses strong knowledge of SQL, Excel, Tableau, Domo, Python and R.

Professional Experience

Senior Business Analyst

The Washington Post, Washington, DC, February 2023-Present

- Technical data lead for Pricing team focused on improving forecasting models, audience segmentation, and launching new ad products.
- Built "Revenue at Risk" dashboard which utilizes Google Ad Manager's forecasting API to estimate ad under-delivery.

Senior Business Intelligence Analyst

The Washington Post, Washington, DC, April 2022-January 2023

- Business Intelligence lead for Zeus Technology, an in-house ad tech company which built a variety of products including a header bidding wrapper, first party audience targeting, and a self-serve ad buying platform.
- Presented analysis of product performance and led integration of client's data into a universal reporting architecture.
- Built forecasting models (regression, financial, and product focused) in Excel and R to predict impact of future product changes and led analysis measuring the effects of these changes.
- Built new data products such as automated alerting for engineering errors, ad speed reporting, first party audience reporting, and bid level reporting based on programmatic auction logs.
- Worked with engineers to build a data backend using Redshift, AWS Athena/S3, and Google BigQuery.

Business Intelligence Analyst

The Washington Post, Washington, DC, April 2021-April 2022

- Managed analytics for programmatic ad product, providing data and analysis to the sales, finance, product, consumer success, and engineering teams.
- Led daily standup mentoring junior analysts and ensuring all tasks in the sprint were on track for completion.
- Represented advertising team in A/B tests, measuring impact of new technologies and site layout changes.
- Automated programmatic reporting using Excel, Python and Domo, reducing time spent on financial and operational reporting by 30 hours per week and unlocking additional metrics for new insights.

Revenue Analyst

Hive Media Group, Carlsbad, CA, August 2019-April 2021

- Analyzed and optimized various channels of programmatic ad revenue including display, native, and video across 20+ sites with over 5 billion ad impressions served monthly.
- Managed analytics and A/B testing for M&A team, completing 3 successful web acquisitions and increased revenue by +50% YoY post acquisition.
- Built statistical model which used expected value to find optimal article length, informing new content strategies.
- Built dashboards in Tableau to analyze ad performance, monitor web traffic, and forecast impression discrepancies.

Education

University of California San Diego

Class of 2019

B.S. Joint Mathematics-Economics, Business Minor

Skills

- Excel: Lookups, Pivot Tables, Modeling, VBA
- Programming: Python, R, Advanced SQL
- BI: Tableau, Looker, Domo, Google Analytics, Redshift, AWS S3, Snowflake, MySQL, BigQuery
- **SQL:** Joins, CTEs, Window Functions, Arrays
- Statistics / Machine Learning: A/B Testing, Time Series Forecasting, Regression, K-Nearest Neighbors, Decision Trees/Random Forest